One of my absolute favorite things to do in the world is to buy a plane ticket somewhere and have no particular plans.
I think that that's the ultimate adventure.
Although, I would say there are some things that you need to know before you go.
First of all, we've already discussed, read up on it.
Know what you're doing, know about the culture, have an idea of what you're in for.
I also like to book a hotel where I'm going to land for a couple of days just to have a plan and just get situated, get over jet lag.
It's somewhat of an orientation of where I am.
Recently, I just went to Bannock, Thailand.
I had been on the plane for 20 hours and delirious with no sleep.
I arrived in Bannock at one in the morning and I was so happy that heated the advice of a man I randomly met getting my oil changed in Los Angeles who told me to go to this particular guest house.
Listen to your fellow travelers.
Ask your friends for advice.
Go to the thorn tree on lonely planet.
There's a pluther of knowledge out there and every thing’s a click away.
Whenever you are at your destination, you can go to tourist agencies in centers of town, airports, train stations, and they can set you up with whatever you need.
If you are arriving to a place where there's a big festival going on, if you're going to the love parade, or carnival, then definitely be responsible and plan ahead if you actually want a bed to sleep in that night, or be ready to party all night long or sleep on the streets.
I've done all of the above and they're definitely pros and cons to all of them.
If you are a by the books planner, then get a travel agent or book things ahead of time and be responsible.
You know how you like to travel, you know if you like to wing it or not.
I think it's an amazing thing to never know where you're going, who you're going to meet or what train you're going to catch.